

Experienced hotelier with demonstrated history of working in the hospitality industry. Talented food & beverages associate with more than 2 years of food service experience. proven ability to manage team, maintain costs, and provide maximum service coverage. capable of building relationships with community and staff.

#### **INTERNSHIPS**

Housekeeping/Front Office/Food and Beverage/Food Production

VIVANTA BY TAJ Bangalore, India MAY 2015 - OCT 2015

#### **SKILLS**

TIME MANAGEMENT SKILLS

RELATIONSHIP DEVELOPMENT

BILINGUAL IN ENGLISH, MALAYALAM

POSITIVE LEARNING PROCESS

**CLIENT-FOCUSED** 

FOOD AND BEVERAGE

COFFEE MAKING

### **LANGUAGES**

ENGLISH

MALAYALAM

HINDI

TAMIL

## WEBSITES & SOCIAL LINKS

LinkedIn: <a href="https://bit.ly/3f9b099">https://bit.ly/3f9b099</a>

Facebook: <a href="https://bit.ly/37iu07B">https://bit.ly/37iu07B</a>

Twitter: <a href="https://bit.ly/3h9A2XE">https://bit.ly/3h9A2XE</a>

## PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of birth 27-Mar-1993

Nationality Indian

Visa status Resident VISA

Marital status Single

## **HOBBIES**

READING, LISTENING TO MUSIC, TRAVELLING, SPORTS..

# ADARSH S CLUSTER F&B ASSOCIATE

Al Satwa Road, Dubai, United Arab Emirates

**\( +971527061549** 

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### IBIS STYLES & GRAND MERCURE DUBAI AIRPORT HOTEL

Dubai, UAE Dec 2019 - Present

#### CLUSTER FOOD AND BEVERAGE ASSOCIATE

- Setting up restaurants, banquet and IRDasper the management plan.
- Ensure the Outlet is set-up for service and supervise for a smooth operation
- Direct and supervise the service team to ensure that all duties are performed as per standards.
- Monitored all food storage and preparation equipment to ensure they were kept in good working condition to maximize cost-efficiency and optimize safe operations.
- Closely monitored shipments, and supervised team members food preparation and handling procedures.
- Daily balanced restaurant cash registers, reconciled transactions, and made bank deposits.
- · Responsible to control portion sizes of menu items to meet budgetary goals.

#### MALABAR INN

Kerala, India May 2018 - Nov 2019

#### FOOD AND BEVERAGE ASSOCIATE

- To ensure safe and sanitary food-handling practices, made sure all food preparation areas were cleaned and inspected.
- Optimized quality assurance procedure by efficiently completing regular line checks.
- Provided efficient and courteous attention to guests by coordinating their stay from sign-in to check-outwhichpromoted loyalty to hotel.
- Supervisedfoodpreparation and food handling to ensure safety procedures were followed.
- Daily balanced restaurant cash registers, reconciled transactions, and made bank deposits.
- Established strong relationships with vendors to ensure inventory supplies were consistently sufficient.
- Experienced how to operate a manual brewer and how to change brew time and bed depth to get the desired coffee profile.

### MEITRA HOSPITAL

Kerala, India Feb2017-Apr2018

## FRONT OFFICE OFFICER

- Responded to telephone inquiries and transferred calls to correct staff members authorized to solve their issues.
- Greeted customers at entrance and provided professional and friendly assistance.
- Screened visitors, updated logs, and issued temporary passes as per protocol to ensure safety of facility.
- Provided accurate costs and fees to patrons, confirmed name of account and processed payments.
- Sent department heads copies of corporate correspondence, memos and updates to keep all staff up-to-date on operations and developments.
- Performed customer payment duties including providing receipts and change.
- Used Arcus to record customer information and updated room vacancies as patients checked out.
- Kept book keeping accurate and up-to-date, printed reports and provided with information about occupancy and revenues everyend of the day.
- Reported guest room issues including guest amenities and requirements to housekeeping and maintenance departments for immediate attention and/or repair.
- Enhance positive first impressions to every visitor by keeping reception area clean and organized.

## **EDUCATION**

IHM -KOZHIKODE Kerala, India 2017 Bachelor

BSc Hospitality and Hotel Administration

RAHMANIYA HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL

Kerala, India 2011

Kerala, India 2009

Higher Secondary School

Computer Science

THIRUVANGOOR HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL

Senior School Leaving Certificate